在上一集中
Previously on Transformers Prime:
简单地说 这种化合物可以让我们数字化整个世界
Simply put, this combination of elements could allow us to cyberform entire worlds.
那我们就先集中手头的所有资源\N全力修复终极之锁吧
Then we will focus upon the successful reconstruction of the Omega Lock.
擎天柱！虎子又露头了
Prime! It's 'Cons again.
而且被我们抓了个正着
In progress this time.
救护车 我们要带回一个霸天虎俘虏
Ratchet, We will be returning with a Decepticon prisoner.
威震天为何要窃取人类科技？
Why is Megatron stealing human technology?
他究竟想要建造什么？
What is he attempting to build?
击倒从汽车人的医生哪里获取了这个未完成配方
Knock out first procured this unfinished shamble from the Autobot medic.
那么最快的解决办法 就是将那名医生弄到手
The most efficient means to an end may be to recruit that medic.
只有大灾变才能毁灭塞博特恩上的巨狰狞种族
It took a cataclysm to extinguish Cybertron's original Predacon inhabitants.
而你根本就不是我的对手 擎天柱
You never stood a chance against me, Prime.
事实上 今天你大限到了！
In fact, the time has come for your extinction.
头儿 可否速战速决？
Permission to hasten our progress, chief?
批准
Granted.
这场战斗可不适合仅有一只手的汽车人
This is no place for a one-handed Autobot.
一只破手换一只好眼 这买卖划算
I'll take one bum hand over one good eye any day.
收手吧 巨狰狞！
Stand down, Predacon.
我是冲云霄！
I am Predaking
而我永远不会向你们屈服！
And I will never bow to your kind!
冲云霄 我得知我们的目标正受到威胁
Predaking, I have been informed that our objective is at risk.
去保护它 快！
Secure it. Now.
指挥官 目标已安全
Commander, objective secured.
现在是你投降的好机会
Now might be a fine time for surrender.
根据逻辑推断 若不是…
A logical assumption, were it not for...
啊…呀！
Ah... aah!
救护车 立即接我们回基地
Ratchet, we require immediate transport back to base.
嗯？
Huh?
空姐 有个家伙正站在我们飞机的翅膀上！
Stewardess, there's a man on the wing of this plane!
救护车 你听到了吗？
Ratchet, do you read?
呃…阿尔茜？
Uh... Arcee...?
隔板
Bulkhead?
一切都好吧？
Is everything all right?
救护车他人呢？
Where's Ratchet?
他…他被掳走了…
He's... he's gone.
你想从我这儿得到什么？
What do you want from me?
事实上 我需要你的协助
Your assistance, actually.
来帮我们完成一个小…科研项目
To help complete a little... science project.
我绝不会合作的
I will never cooperate.
震荡波可不需要你的合作…
Shockwave does not require your cooperation
来汲取你脑中的知识 医生
to siphon your knowledge, doctor.
只打掉激光鸟的一点喷漆而已
Peeled some paint off Laserbeak.
假如我枪法再好点 救护车就不会被劫走了
But if I were a better shot, Ratchet would still be here.
不要气馁 士兵 我们已经检查了整层楼
Chin up, soldier. We've combed the entire floor.
到目前为止 那是我们找到的唯一线索
For the moment, that remains our only clue.
环陆桥记录也毫无用处
Nothing in the groundbridge log.
虽然他们是用环陆桥将人带走的
If they bridged Ratchet out of here
但那是他们的桥 而不是我们的
They used theirs, not ours.
为什么只抓走了救护车 而对他们俩置之不理？
Why take Ratchet prisoner, but leave these two behind?
如果威震天想将我们的医生掳为人质
If Megatron intends to hold our medic hostage
我很奇怪他竟然没有提赎金
I find it curious that he's made no demands.
我们有理由相信 救护车手中应该有某种霸天虎想要的东西
It would stand to reason that Ratchet must possess something the Decepticons want.
无论虎子们想要什么 老救是不会给他们的
Well, whatever the 'Cons are after, Ratch won't give it up.
对吧？
Right?
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron
我听说您将一个该死的汽车人带到了这艘战舰上
I understand that you have brought an accursed Autobot aboard this warship.
确实如此
Indeed.
那么我和擎天柱没算完的账 就用他结吧
Then I will accomplish with him what I failed to with the Prime.
冲云霄 这名汽车人可不只是俘虏
Predaking, this Autobot is more than a prisoner.
你难道不想修复塞博特恩了么？
You do wish for Cybertron's restoration, do you not?
不过他的价值终会消失
Our captive's usefulness will come to an end.
等到那个时候 我向你保证
And when that time arrives, I assure you
他将任由你处置
he will be all yours.
听着 我需要全天候卫星监控
Listen, I need 24/7 satellite monitoring.
无论是天上飞的 还是地上跑的 都给我盯紧了！
Eyes on the skies and ears to the ground!
或许铁桶头想得到某个技术玩意
Maybe buckethead's after the techno-babble.
合成能量的配方？
The synth-en formula?
虎子已控制了这星球上几乎所有的能量\N还要合成的玩意儿干什么？
Why would the 'Cons need the artificial stuff If they already control most of this planet's energon reserves?
还能为啥 贪婪呗
Greed, what else?
如果威震天真的如救护车推测的那样
If Megatron is truly rebuilding the Omega Lock
在试图重铸终极之锁
As Ratchet surmised
那么合成能量可能是一种不可或缺的原料
Synthetic energon might be a necessary component.
我不想火上浇油
I hate to be the one to bring lightning to a thunderstorm
但有一件事你们全都忽略了！
But there's one thing we're all ignoring.
如果虎子们在这里抓走了救护车\N那么他们已经知道了这个基地的位置
If the 'Cons found Ratchet here, they know the location of this base.
那么 大脑神经接入器获取了什么信息？
And what did the cortical psychic patch yield?
只确认了合成能量的配方确实不稳定
Only confirmation that the synthetic energon formula Is unstable
并且 汽车人医生对此项目的研究还未完成
and that the Autobot medic's work on it remains incomplete.
看来我们必须帮助救护车完成他的研究
Then it seems we must help Ratchet finish his work.
你在我的脑袋里折腾够了么？
Are you through poking around inside my head?
没找到你想要的东西 是吧？
You didn't find what you wanted, did you?
否则你也不会露面了
Or else you wouldn't be here.
很明显 我想要的东西目前还不存在
What I want apparently does not yet exist.
那东西是…？
And that would be...?
我们非常期待你能完成合成能量配方的研究
We would very much like for you to complete your work on the formula for synthetic energon.
就算我能做到 但你觉得我会把用之不竭的能量和弹药拱手相送
Even if I were capable, do you think that I would hand you a limitless supply of fuel and ammunition just
让你拿去对付汽车人吗？
so you can turn around and use it against the Autobots?
哦 你完全误会我们了 亲爱的救护车
Oh, you misunderstand, dearest Ratchet.
我将把这个配方用于创造
I intend to use your formula for the purpose of creation
而非毁灭
Not destruction.
我们偶然发现 将你的合成能量与C.N.A.融合
We have fortuitously discovered that your synth-en, when combined with cyber-nucleic acid
是制造一种塞博特恩网状物替代品的基础
May in fact form the basis for an alternative cyber-matter.
你果然是想重铸终极之锁
You are attempting to rebuild the Omega Lock.
只要你我二人向前迈一小步\N就可以创造历史的伟大一刻
We stand on the verge of a great moment in time, you and I.
复苏我们的家园
The restoration of our very homeworld.
通过与你合作？那个毁灭我们家园的罪魁祸首？
Collaborate with the barbarian who essentially destroyed our planet in the first place?
那个面对面残忍地摧毁了大黄蜂发声器的野蛮人？
Who sadistically crushed Bumblebee's voice box while looking him in the eye?
不 谢谢了
No, thank you.
那么你就要做出选择了
Then I present you with a choice:
或者完成你的研究 或者…
Complete your research, or...
哼哼哼 人类永远是你们的弱点
Heh... humans, always the weak link.
你觉得这些人类对我很重要么？
Are these humans supposed to mean something to me?
如果他们不重要的话 我肯定这很重要
If not, I am certain this will.
你一定很清楚
As you must certainly be aware
我们已经掌握了你们基地的位置
We know the location of your current base.
乖乖与我合作\N我保证你的汽车人同伙和人类宠物会安然无恙
Accept my offer, and I will allow your fellow Autobots and human pets to remain unharmed.
好好考虑吧 善良的医生
Think it over, good doctor.
我的君王 您不会真的放过那些汽车人吧？
My liege, you aren't really going to allow the Autobots to remain operational?
当然不会
Of course not.
立刻召集你的部队 红蜘蛛
Assemble your armada, Starscream
去再次摧毁他们的基地吧
And decimate their base once again.
唉 所有空中搜索模式都一无所获
All aerial search patterns are coming up empty.
也未拦截到虎子的任何通讯
No comm-link chatter either.
也没有任何地面活动
And no ground activity.
虎子们安静得有点过了
It's a little too quiet out there.
鉴于霸天虎已不再搜索巨狰狞骸骨或地球科技
Since the Decepticons no longer seek Predacon bones or Earth technology
我们已无法追踪任何东西了
there is no activity to track.
那么在威震天有所行动之前 我们只能静观其变了
So until Megatron makes a move, we're in a holding pattern.
救护车觉得他为我造的这只新手并不够好
Ratchet didn't think this new hand he built for me was good enough.
但我告诉你们什么才是真正的不够好
But I'll tell you what truly isn't good enough:
那就是放弃
Giving up.
我们已别无选择 只能使用一些老办法了
We have no choice but to play this old school
分散成小队搜索 尽可能覆盖最大的范围
Split into teams, for maximum coverage.
敌军来袭！是一整支舰队！
We have incoming. A whole fleet's worth.
集中火力打E机库
Concentrate your fire on hangar E.
空军正在抵挡他们 但只是暂时的
Air cover's holding. For the moment.
威震天陛下 我非常高兴地向您汇报
Lord Megatron, I am pleased to report
汽车人的基地已被夷为平地了
that the Autobot base has been reduced to ashes.
食堂这下成了“屎堂”
The mess hall sure is a mess.
我们很幸运 仅靠简单的伪装就骗过了霸天虎
We are fortunate that Decepticons can be fooled by a simple paint job.
我觉得让你放开手脚 你才有心情去参观我们的设施
I'm sure you would more fully appreciate a tour of our facilities if you were comfortable.
你怎么知道我不会用这些给自己截肢
How do you know I won't use these to amputate?
那你可就没机会欣赏我们的分子伪装力场了
And pass up a chance to see our molecular masking field?
你的隐形装置
Your cloaking device.
不过一个力场而已 没什么技术含量
Shielding is shielding, high tech or low.
或许我们的能量注入电容器能让你刮目相看呢？
Perhaps you'll be more impressed by our energon transfusion capacitor.
它可以让我们的能量消耗上限扩大一千倍
It allows us to maximize our Consumption a thousand-fold.
霸天虎的工程科技 确实令人刮目相看
Decepticon engineering never fails to impress.
医生 虽然我们是死敌
Doctor, we may be mortal enemies
但汽车人与霸天虎却有一个共同的目标
But Autobots and Decepticons do share one common goal.
你们应该期盼我们被毁灭的家园恢复昔日的辉煌吧？
You would like to see the ruins of our devastated homeworld restored to their former brilliance
而我也一样
As would I.
威震天 你不过是想再次征服塞博特恩
Megatron, you would just try to conquer Cybertron All over again
并奴役所有拒绝效忠你的人
And enslave anyone who refuses to pledge allegiance to you.
我当然会那么做！
Of course I would!
而你的战友将会一如既往地尝试阻止我
And your comrades would attempt to stop me, as ever.
但至少 我们再次拥有了一颗可以为之战斗的星球
But at least we would once again possess a planet worth fighting over.
或许吧 但你不会满足于此的 是吧？
Perhaps, but you wouldn't stop there, would you?
地球是你的第二个目标 或者是第一个
Earth would be next, if not first.
我如何确定你不会对人类下手
What assurance do I have that you would leave humankind be?
并在你得到想要的东西后将我卸磨杀驴？
And that you wouldn't instantly terminate me once you get what you need?
完全没法确定
None whatsoever.
毕竟你我都心知肚明
After all, we both know that as a Decepticon
我们霸天虎的承诺一钱不值
any assurances I might offer would be worthless.
但你或许是塞博特恩重见天日的唯一希望
But that does not change the fact that you may be Cybertron's only hope of ever seeing life again.
这一事实不会因此而改变
这么说 这小子打下了激光鸟应答器的功能终端
So the kid clipped the business end of Laserbeak's transponder.
看来你的枪法还是不错的
You're not such a bad shot after all.
我们就知道 老救不在 你就是分析情报的最佳人选
We thought you might be the best one to provide an analysis
In Ratchet's absence.
它正在尝试与霸天虎战舰进行通讯
It's trying to communicate with the warship.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know?
它正在告诉我们
It's telling us.
嗯 拉夫 那是塞博特恩代码
Uh, Raf, that's Cybertronian code.
等等 拉夫先是能听懂大黄蜂说话
Wait, first Raf understands Bumblebee
现在又能看懂塞博特恩文字？
Now he reads Cybertronian?
我们确定他不是一个外星人么？
Are we sure he's not some kind of alien?
我已经断断续续学了一段时间了
I've been learning for a while, in between stuff
救护车有空时 就会教我一些
when Ratchet had time to teach me.
嘿 拉夫 我们会把他救回来的
Hey, Raf, we'll bring him back.
哪怕拼上性命
If it's the last thing we do.
如果它正在和它的老妈聊天 我们能否追踪这个信号？
If it's talking to its momma can we triangulate the signal?
追踪一艘被护盾保护着的战舰？
To a shielded warship?
如果这个应答器仍在激光鸟身上\N我们就可以跟踪它
If the transponder were still attached to Laserbeak, We could follow it.
或许我们该给它装副翅膀
Maybe we should give it wings.
我们可以使用加工车间的零配件
We can use spare parts from the machine shop.
那么咱们开工吧 为了大夫
Then let's do it, for the doc.
当你千方百计地夺取我们的资源时
While your forces have put a dent in our resources
震荡波一直在努力升级我们的实验室
Shockwave has been invaluable in updating our laboratory.
如果你答应合作
Should you choose to accept the task
你将可以不受限制地使用我们的设备
You shall have unrestricted access to our equipment.
这居然是量子低温诱导器？
Is that a quantum cryo-inducer?
这东西只建造过两台
Only two were ever made.
事实上 是三台
Three, actually.
你手中的是最初的原型机
You are holding the original prototype.
频率调节器总是短路！
The frequency modulator keeps shorting out!
放松点 孩子 我去检查一下电线
Easy, champ. Let me try uncrossing some wires.
这情景可真少见
Now there's something you don't see every day.
老千从前并不是个独行侠
Ie wasn't always a loner, you know.
作为雷霆救援队员 队伍永远是第一位的
Being a Wrecker was all about the team.
别 别 别！
Yip-ip-ip-ip!
神子！那个我还有用呐！
Miko! I needed that!
我只是想弄紧那个什么玩意
I was just trying to tighten up that thingamajig.
切！拉倒吧！
Pfff! Please!
福勒探员
Agent fowler.
你没事吧？
Everything all right?
就是有点心事
Just preoccupied.
我在想最近我们从虎子手中死里逃生的情景
Thinking about the close calls We humans have had with the 'Cons lately.
被声波打倒在地 和你妈妈一起被关在击倒的后备箱里
Smacked down by Soundwave, stuck in Knock out's trunk with your mom.
这个就甭提了
Moving on...
让人忧心的是
the uncomfortable reality is
汽车人不会一直留在这里
The 'bots might not always be here.
即使他们在 他们也不能同时出现在所有地方
And even if they are, they can't be everywhere at once
我们已经有过教训
as we've learned.
这副盔甲是当时唯一能保护神子免遭巨狰狞毒手的东西
This armor is the only thing that stood between Miko and that Predacon.
正是因为它 神子才能毫发无伤
The reason she came back without a scratch.
这类塞博特恩科技可能正是我们需要的
Cyber-tech like that could be just what we need
使我们前线的探员 在面对强敌时获得一线生机
To give our agents on the front lines a fighting chance.
将来 你也很可能成为其中的一员
Agents like, maybe you someday.
我？！
What?!
你很快就够年龄了 而且你是个领袖坯子 孩子
You'll be of age soon, and you're Prime material, son.
你妈妈觉得你很适合这项工作
Your mom thought you might be a good fit
鉴于你目前对自己的未来毫无打算
seeing as you've been wishy-washy about future plans.
等等 你经常和我妈妈聊天？聊我的事？
Wait, you've been talking to my mom? About me?
卡斯特的胡子！
Custer's mustache!
（Custer 卡斯特 美国南北战争时期的将军\N以不怕死著称 由于部下伤亡过大 不太受官兵拥戴）
抱歉 福勒探员
Sorry, Agent Fowler.
看来我得换条星条旗短裤了
I think I need to change my star-spangled shorts.
我仍在调校芯片的遥控功能
I'm still fine-tuning chip's remote.
芯片？
Chip?
也就是说 我们要让这个小玩意飞回虎子的指挥中心
So we're gonna let this doohickey fly back to 'con central...
并给我们指明救护车的位置
And lead us right to Ratchet.
即使你能重铸终极之锁
Even if you manage to reconstruct the Omega Lock
但很久以前我就意识到 它是一种神秘的力量
It is a mystic force. I've come to my senses.
使用技术复制其能力是完全不可能的
The notion of scientifically replicating its capability Is pure folly.
甚至可以称为痴心妄想！
Madness, even.
但医生 如果我们不去尝试 如何确定这不可行呢？
But how will we ever know for certain, doctor... if we do not try?
而当万事俱备之际 我们何不放手一试呢？
And how can we not try, When the means finally lie within our reach?
火种源在上
By the Allspark
你真的成功了
you've actually done it.
拜霸天虎工程技术所赐
Decepticon engineering.
用不了多久 终极之锁就可以全力运作了
It will not take long for this Omega Lock's drives to be fully operational.
那么复苏我们家园所唯一欠缺的
All that is still needed to restore our home
就是它所产生的塞博特恩网状物
is the cyber-matter to launch through it.
这需要一个稳定的配方来生产合成能量
Which requires a stabilized formula for the production of synthetic energon.
我对你完全有信心 医生
I have every confidence in you, doctor.
我答应你
I'll do it.
而这早就在你的预料之中 是不是？
But then you already knew that, didn't you?